Hamza Tahir

Karachi • +92 335 3733089 • hamzatatwork1@gmail.com • <u>linkedin.com/in/hamza-tahir-49618a1b2</u> • <u>https://github.com/Hamza-Tahirr</u>

Al Developer & Full Stack Engineer

With 4 years of extensive experience as an AI Developer & Full Stack Engineer, I've honed my skills across a spectrum of cutting-edge technologies. My journey has taken me through renowned companies like Octa Security, Adsvol, and Tally Marks Consulting, where I've made significant contributions to diverse projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

TallyMarks Consulting (TMC) • Karachi • Full-time • 10/2023 - Present

TMC (TallyMarks Consulting) is a leading provider of digital transformation solutions. TMC has established itself as the largest and top SAP Partner in Pakistan and a Qlik Master Reseller. With hundreds of clients globally, TMC has a proven track record of delivering innovative and effective solutions that meet the unique needs of each client.

SAP BTP Consultant

- Streamlined project management process resulting in 30% reduction in project completion time.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to develop and implement customized SAP BTP solutions, resulting in 100% client satisfaction and 10% increase in revenue.
- Developed custom SAP CAI interface for 3 clients, resulting in a 15% increase in user engagement and improved data accuracy.

Adsvol • Part-time • 08/2021 - Present

Software Developer

- Implemented automated testing process that increased code coverage by 70%, resulting in a 40% decrease in software bugs and improved product quality.
- Utilized advanced NLP techniques and LLMs to enhance the performance of chatbots, resulting in a 25% decrease in customer wait time.

Wolters Kluwer • Remote • Part-time • 07/2023 - 10/2023

Power BI Developer

- Designed and developed interactive dashboards and reports using Power BI for Wolters Kluwer
- Implemented data transformations, calculated measures, and optimized query performance to enhance reporting efficiency.
- Leveraged MySQL database to establish seamless data connections and integrate diverse data sources.
- Conducted data analysis and interpreted key findings to provide actionable insights for business stakeholders.

Qanare Engineering • Internship • 05/2022 - 07/2023 Data Analyst

- Contributed to various data analysis projects, collaborating with a team to generate insightful database reports
- Underwent training for Ignition 8.1 Credential Courses

 One of my most significant accomplishments was leading a team of three members for a fully sponsored Final Year Project titled "SCADA and Industry 4.0 Based Textile Plant Monitoring System."

EDUCATION

Electrical Engineering

Usman Institute Of Technology • GPA: 3.2

CERTIFICATIONS

Discovering SAP Business Technology Platform

SAP • 01/2024 - Present

Postman API Fundamentals Student Expert

Postman • 12/2023 - Present

Composing and automating with SAP Build the No-Code Way

SAP • 12/2023 - Present

Data Science And Al Bootcamp

DataMites • 09/2022 - Present

Python Certificate

HackerRank • 05/2022 - Present

PROJECTS

Youtube Scrapper

Upwork

Extracting Transcript from Youtube

Medical Multimodal LLMs

Adsvol

Medical-Help-using-Multimodal-LLM

Conversational AI Chatbot

TallyMarks Consulting

Conversational-Al-Chatbot-with-Langchain

SKILLS

Al Development: Langchain, Al Chatbots, Pinecone, OpenAl, LLAMA, TensorFlow, DialogFlow

Full Stack Development: Python, Langchain, TypeScript, React, Al Chatbots, Next.js, Streamlit, Pandas, Numpy, Power Bl, Seaborn